Contact



+1 226-606-6590



orusaishtiaq@gmail.com



<u>linkedin.com/orusa-akhtar</u>



github.com/orusaish



orusaish.github.io

Technical Skills

JavaScript
HTML
CSS
Python
Bash
Java
C#

Frameworks

C/C++

Node.js MongoDB MySQL Express HandleBars Sequelize React Firebase Axios JQuery Git

Orusa Akhtar

Summary

I am a full stack web developer with a passion for front end web development and back end development. I enjoy working in a team and collaboration to create meaningful web applications. Certified in full stack web development from the University of Toronto and holding master's in computer applications, I have experience in web development using the MERN stack and latest industry standards.

Projects

ParkEZ





- A web app that helps truckers and truck companies reserve and view parking spaces
- Built using React, Nodejs, Express, JavaScript, Sequelize, Passport, axios, bootstrap and MySQL

Train Scheduler



- A web app to display train arrival and departure information
- Built using moment.js, HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Bamazon





- An Amazon like storefront that helps maintain inventory and customer support
- Built using MySQL and Nodejs

Experience

Home Tutor 2006-2011

Tutored Math for middle and high school students

Math and Science Teacher

2004-2006

Taught math and science to grade 9 and 10 students in the International Indian School, Jeddah

Assistant Computer Science Professor

2002-2004

Sri Sathya Sai Arts and Science college, Bhopal India

- Taught data structures and database management systems
- Assisted students in programming assignments and debugging issues

Education

Full stack web development

University of Toronto, Mississauga

Master of Computer Application (MCA)

Samrat Ashok Technological Institute, Vidisha, India

Bachelor of Science (BSc)

Barkatullah University, Bhopal India